limeade.com 2018-12-04

# Limeade

## Limeade Privacy Policy

Effective Date: November 16, 2017  
This Privacy Policy applies to information that Limeade, Inc. (“ **Limeade** ,” “our,” “we” or “us”) collects on Limeade.com and Limeade’s private-label websites and applications (collectively, the “Services”).

**Your privacy is important to us. Please read this Privacy Policy to learn about the information that Limeade collects from you and how Limeade uses that information.**

**BY USING THE SERVICES YOU CONSENT TO THE COLLECTION, USE AND TRANSFER OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA AS DESCRIBED IN THIS PRIVACY POLICY. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH ANY PART OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY, THEN PLEASE DO NOT USE THE SERVICES.**

Please be aware that LIMEADE and all associated Services and systems are housed on servers in the United States. If you are located outside of the United States, information we collect (including cookies) are processed and stored in the United States, which may not offer the same level of privacy protection as the country where you reside or are a citizen. By using the Services and providing information to us, you consent to the transfer to and processing of the information in the United States.

**1\. SCOPE**

This Privacy Policy describes the information that Limeade collects (directly or indirectly) and why we collect it, what we do with the information we collect and how you can manage your Personal Data (defined below).

This Privacy Policy does not apply to any website or service that does not display or link to this Privacy Policy.

Our agreements with certain customers may contain provisions about the collection, use, storage and disposal of Personal Data collected through the Services and offline. If a provision of a customer agreement conflicts or otherwise is inconsistent with a provision of this Privacy Policy, then the provision of the customer agreement will prevail but solely to the extent of the conflict or inconsistency.

This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and made a part of Limeade’s Terms of Service. If you have not done so already, please also review the Terms of Service.

**2\. INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

**Personal Data** is information that directly or indirectly identifies you, such as your name, email address and information about your health.

**Protected Health Information (“PHI”)** is subset of Personal Data that is health information subject to the U.S. Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (“ **HIPAA** ”). Limeade must comply with HIPAA when Limeade’s customer is a health plan sponsored by an employer for its employees (known as “covered entities” under HIPAA). When Limeade collects or processes PHI for or on behalf of a covered entity, Limeade is a “business associate” under HIPAA.

**Other Information** is information that, by itself does not individually identify you, such as browser type, operating system, the webpages you viewed and how long you viewed them.

We may link together different types of Other Information or link Other Information to Personal Data. If linked information directly or indirectly identifies an individual person, Limeade treats the linked information as Personal Data.

In this Privacy Policy, to “ **process** ” Personal Data means to perform any operation on Personal Data, whether or not by automated means, such as collection, recording, organizing, storing, adapting, use, disclosure, combining, erasing or destroying.

**3\. HOW WE COLLECT INFORMATION**

Limeade collects information:

**From your employer** : Your employer provides information to Limeade such as:

  * Email address
  * Name
  * Date of Birth
  * Address
  * Employee ID number (if applicable)
  * Social Security Number (if Employee ID number is unavailable)
  * Gender (optional)
  * Geographic region where user works (if applicable)
  * Corporate department of user (if applicable)
  * Health Insurance Provider (if applicable) 
  * Country (if applicable)
  * Telephone Number (optional)

**When you register for the Services** : When you register for the Services, we collect the user name and password that you select. When registering for the Services, we encourage you to select a username that does not, by itself, identify you to others because we use the username to make various communications to individuals participating in programs available through the Services, such as leaderboards, activity feeds and social networking features.

When you use the Services: We collect information about the Services that you use and how you use them, such as wellness assessments and goal tracking, medical conditions, health, lifestyle, diet, exercise habits, drug and alcohol usage, workplace matters and other relevant Personal Data relating to your wellness.

**Through Server Logs** : A server log is a list of the activities that a server performs. Limeade’s servers automatically collect and store in server logs your search queries, Internet Protocol (IP) address, hardware settings, browser type, browser language, the date and time of your request and referral URL and certain cookies that identify your browser or Limeade account.

**Biometric Information From Wearables** : When you connect your wearable fitness tracker, heart rate monitor, pedometer or like technology (your “ **Wearable** ”) with the Services, we collect information about your steps, athletic or recreational activities, exercise frequency and information about nutrition, such as calorie intake, nutritional statistics, blood pressure and other biometric data.

**From Your Computer, Tablet or Mobile Telephone** : We collect information about your computer, tablet or mobile telephone (“ **Device** ”), such as model, operating system version, mobile network information, telephone number, internet service provider and similar identifiers. Limeade may associate your Device information with your Limeade account. We may collect and store information (including Personal Data) on your Device through browser web and web application data caches.

We may from time to time offer mobile applications (“ **Apps** ”). When we offer Apps, we may collect information about your use of and interaction with the App, such as your Device’s operating system, browser type, domain and other system settings, search queries, the country and time zone in which your Device is located, metadata and other information stored on your Device, as permitted by your operating system settings.

We may collect information from sensors that provide Limeade with information on nearby devices, Bluetooth address, Wi-Fi access points and information made available by you or others that indicates the current or prior location of the user. We also may collect IP address and MAC address. How we collect this data depends on how you access the Services. Certain Services may collect this data even when you are not actively using the Services.

**Through Data Collection Technology** : We use cookies, pixel tabs (also known as web beacons, flash cookies and clear GIFs) and similar technology (“ **Data Collection Technology** ”) to automatically collect information (including Other Information) about you when you use the Services. Please read below to learn more about how Limeade uses Data Collection Technology. Limeade generally does not treat Other Information as Personal Data unless required by applicable law.

**4\. DATA COLLECTION TECHNOLOGY**

Data Collection Technology collects all sorts of information, such as how long you spend on various webpages in the Services, which webpages you view, your search queries, error and performance reports, as well as Device identifier or IP address, browser type, time zone and language settings and operating system.

Data Collection Technology deployed through the Services includes cookies and web beacons.

**Web Beacons** : A web beacon (also called a pixel tag or clear GIF) is computer code that communicates information from your device to a server. Some of Limeade’s content and emails may contain embedded web beacons that allow a server to read certain types of information from your Device, allow us to count the number of people who have viewed content, to know when you opened an email message and the IP address of your Device. Web beacons help Limeade develop statistical information to provide better and more personalized content.

**Cookies** : Cookies are small text files that are sent to or accessed from your web browser or your computer’s hard drive. A cookie typically contains the name of the domain (internet location) from which the cookie originated, the “lifetime” of the cookie (i.e., when it expires) and a randomly generated unique number or similar identifier. A cookie also may contain information about your computer, such as user settings, browsing history and activities conducted while using the Services.

The Services use the following cookies:

  * Strictly necessary cookies, which are required for the operation of the Services. Without them, for example, you would not be able to register or log in for the Services that Limeade offers.
  * Analytical/performance cookies, which allow Limeade to recognize and count the number of visitors, learn how visitors navigate the Services and improve the Services.
  * Functionality cookies, which Limeade uses to recognize you when you return to the Services.

To learn more about cookies and web beacons, visit www.allaboutcookies.org.

Limeade also uses analytics services, such as Google Analytics, to collect Other Information. Generally analytics services do not identify individual users. Many analytics services allow you to opt out of data collection. For example, to learn more about Google Analytics practices and to opt out, visit www.google.com/settings/ads or by downloading the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on at <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

**How Limeade Uses Data Collection Technology** : Some Data Collection Technology is deployed by Limeade when you visit the Services. Other Data Collection Technology is deployed by third parties with which Limeade partners to deliver the Services.

Data Collection Technology helps us improve your experience of the Services by, measuring the success of campaigns, compiling statistics about use of the Services and helping us analyze technical and navigational information about the Services.

We also may use Data Collection Technology to collect information from the device that you use to access the Services, such as your operating system type, browser type, domain and other system settings, as well as the language your system uses and the country and time zone in which your computer or device is located.

**Your Control of Cookies** : Some web browsers (including some mobile web browsers) provide settings that allow you to control or reject cookies or to alert you when a cookie is placed on your device. Although you are not required to accept cookies or mobile device identifiers, if you block or reject them, you may not have access to all features available through the Services.

**Do Not Track** : Some web browsers (including Safari, Internet Explorer, Firefox and Chrome) incorporate a “Do Not Track” (“ **DNT** ”) or similar feature that signals to websites that a user does not want to have his or her online activity and behavior tracked. If a website that responds to a particular DNT signal receives the DNT signal, the browser can block that website from collecting certain information about the browser’s user. Not all browsers offer a DNT option and DNT signals are not yet uniform. For this reason, many website operators, including Limeade, do not respond to DNT signals.

**5\. HOW WE PROCESS PERSONAL DATA**

Limeade processes Personal Data:

  * To set up and maintain your registration with the Services;
  * To communicate with you;
  * To deliver relevant content to you; 
  * To provide features through the Services, such as social networking options; 
  * To prevent and investigate fraud and other misuses of the Services;
  * To protect our rights and property;
  * To operate, manage and improve the Services; and 
  * To ensure the technical functionality and security of the Services.

Limeade processes Other Information:

  * To administer and improve the Services and your experience on the Services;
  * To analyze trends and gather broad aggregate demographic information;
  * To statistically monitor how many people are using the Services or opening our emails;
  * To develop, improve and protect the Services;
  * For audience research;
  * To audit and analyze the Services; and
  * To ensure the technical functionality and security of the Services.

**6\. HOW WE SHARE INFORMATION**

We may share Personal Data collected via the Services with:

  * **Third-Party Wellness Providers** : Limeade may disclose relevant Personal Data about you to third parties that we have engaged to provide health management, behavioral coaching or similar wellness-related services (“ **Third-Party Wellness Providers** ”). Third-Party Wellness Providers may contact you to offer their services in support of your health and well-being management goals.  
Limeade and its Third-Party Wellness Providers, as well as other Limeade business partners, also may share Personal Data about you to administer activities and challenges you select (“ **Partner Challenges** ”) and to award you with incentives and other rewards you earn through participation in Partner Challenges. Limeade contractually obligates Third-Party Wellness Providers and other Limeade business partners to safeguard Personal Data about you in substantially the same manner that Limeade safeguards it. If you accept the services offered by a Third-Party Wellness Provider or decide to participate in a Partner Challenge, such agreement is solely between you and the Third-Party Wellness Provider or applicable Limeade business partner because they are separate and distinct entities from Limeade.
  * **Other Service Providers** : Limeade shares information with Limeade’s other third-party service providers that perform services on our behalf, such as incentive fulfillment, web hosting, translation or data storage. Limeade will ensure that any service provider with which we share Personal Data agrees to safeguard it in substantially the same manner as Limeade has described in this Privacy Policy and in accordance with all applicable laws. If you choose to use our translation service, your username along with certain Personal Data will be provided to the translation service provider in order to provide you with the requested translations. If you are using the translation service, we recommend that you choose a username that does not explicitly identify you. For purposes of clarity, “username” means a unique set of characters (alphabetic and numeric) that you choose to identify you on the Services upon registration. We encourage you to select a username that does not identify you to others and to keep the username confidential.
  * **Employers and Health Plans** :  Limeade may disclose Personal Data to your employer, health plan or group health plan. Sometimes, a group health plan is sponsored and administered by your employer and, in some cases, administered by other employees. (In general, health plans are covered entities as defined under HIPAA.) Limeade discloses Personal Data (some of which may be PHI) to your employer or health plan to provide you or your spouse or domestic partner with incentives and rewards for participation in the Services. Limeade will limit the amount of Personal Data shared to the minimum necessary for you to receive the incentives and rewards.

Limeade may aggregate information collected though the Services and remove identifiers so that the information no longer identifies or can be used to identify an individual (“ **Anonymized Information** ”). Limeade shares Anonymized Information with third parties (including our corporate customers that sponsor group health plans) and does not limit third parties' use of the Anonymized Information because it is no longer Personal Data.  
Limeade may share Personal Data if Limeade is involved in a merger, sale, acquisition, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution, bankruptcy or other change of ownership or control (in whole or in part). Limeade requires that the shared Personal Data remain subject to the promises made in the then-current Privacy Policy, unless and until you agree to a new privacy terms.  
Applicable law may require Limeade to disclose your Personal Data if: (i) reasonably necessary to comply with legal process (such as a court order, subpoena or search warrant) or other legal requirements; (ii) disclosure would mitigate Limeade’s liability in an actual or threatened lawsuit; (iii) necessary to protect legal rights of Limeade, users, customers, business partners or other interested parties; or (iv) necessary for the prevention or detection of crime (subject in each case to applicable law). For residents of the European Economic Area, Limeade will disclose Personal Data only when permitted to do so under applicable European and EU Member States’ national data protection laws and regulations.

**7\. CHILDREN’S PRIVACY**  
The Services are not directed to or intended for use by minors. Consistent with the requirements of applicable law, if we learn that we have received any information directly from a minor without his or her parent’s verified consent, we will use that information only to respond directly to that child (or his or her parent or legal guardian) to inform the minor that he or she cannot use the Services and subsequently will delete that information.

**8\. SECURITY OF PERSONAL DATA**  
Limeade takes precautions intended to help protect information that we process but no system or electronic data transmission is completely secure. Any transmission of your Personal Data is at your own risk and we expect that you will use appropriate security measures to protect your Personal Data.

You are responsible for maintaining the security of your account credentials for the Services. Limeade will treat access to the Services through your account credentials as authorized by you. Unauthorized access to password-protected or secure areas is prohibited and may lead to criminal prosecution. We may suspend your use of all or part of the Services without notice if we suspect or detect any breach of security. If you believe that information you provided to us is no longer secure, please notify us immediately using the contact information provided below.

If we become aware of a breach that affects the security of your Personal Data, we will provide you or your employer with notice as required by applicable law. To the extent permitted by applicable law, Limeade will provide any such notice that Limeade must provide to you at your account’s email address. By using the Services, you agree to accept notice electronically.  
If you are accessing the Services through an employer or health plan portal or other third party website, we strongly encourage you to review and understand their privacy policies prior to providing information to us or them that you consider to be sensitive or personal in nature.  
We retain Personal Data in identifiable form only for as long as necessary to fulfill the purposes for which the Personal Data was provided to Limeade or, if longer to comply with law legal obligations, to resolve disputes, to enforce agreements and similar essential purposes.

**9\. PRIVACY SHIELD**  
Limeade complies with the EU-US Privacy Shield Framework and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Frameworks administered by the US Department of Commerce (together, “ **Privacy Shield** ”) regarding the processing of Personal Data (as defined below) from European Union member countries and Switzerland. This means that Limeade certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice; Choice; Accountability for Onward Transfer; Security; Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation; Access; and Recourse, Enforcement, and Liability. If you are a resident of the European Economic Area, please see our Privacy Shield Policy for information about our data protection practices for personal data that we receive from European Union member countries and Switzerland pursuant to their respective Privacy Shield frameworks.

For purposes of enforcing compliance with the Privacy Shield, Limeade is subject to the investigatory and enforcement authority of the US Federal Trade Commission. For more information about the Privacy Shield, see the US Department of Commerce's Privacy Shield website located at [https://www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/).

**10\. YOUR CHOICES ABOUT YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

  * **The right to know what Personal Data we hold about you** : If you would like to know the Personal Data that Limeade maintains about you, please contact us in writing using the contact information below. If you are a registered user, you can review certain Personal Data that you provided to Limeade by logging in to your account. If you are not a registered user, Limeade may take reasonable steps to verify your identity before providing access to Personal Data.
  * **The right to correct or delete Personal Data** : The easiest way to correct or delete certain Personal Data that you have provided to the Services is to log in to your account and enter the necessary changes in your profile settings. If you have additional questions regarding the correction or deletion of the Personal Data we hold about you, please contact us using the contact information below. Please be reminded that we will review your request but may be restricted in our ability to change or delete your Personal Data. If the Services are made available to you by a corporate customer that is sponsoring your use of the Services, your eligibility to receive Incentives and Rewards from such parties, if any are offered, may be adversely affected by your election to remove Personal Data about you from the Services. You must contact the corporate customer directly for further information.

**11\. CHANGES TO THE PRIVACY POLICY**  
If we change this Privacy Policy, we will post the updated Privacy Policy and its effective date on this page. If Limeade makes material changes that reduce your privacy rights, Limeade will notify you in advance by sending you an email and/or by posting a notice in the Services.

**12\. HOW TO CONTACT US**  
If you have any questions, comments, or concerns about how we handle your Personal Data, then you may contact us through our Customer Support Team at [help@limeade.com](mailto:help@limeade.com) or write to us at:

Limeade, Inc.  
Attention: Data Protection Officer  
10885 N.E. 4th St., Suite 400  
Bellevue, WA 98004  
1-888-830-9830
